WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Daisy, put that into the oven.
Ohh!
Have you chosen what you want yet?
Whatever you think best.
That doesn't sound like a bride
on the brink of wedded bliss!
It's a long time since I've
been on the brink of anything.
Except possibly the grave.
I wanted a big wedding breakfast.
All of us sat at groaning
tables having a jolly time.
- Why can't you have that?
- It's not how posh people do it.
They stand about with nibbly bits stuck in
their teeth and that's what we've to do.
I don't see why. We could put
trestle tables up in the hall.
No, Mr Carson wants it like
the family would do it.
I don't mind.
Not really.
- So what are you going to wear?
- My brown day dress.
Anna is going to tidy it up a bit.
It's simple, but I'm sure it will be fine.
Because I've got a new
catalogue. It's so easy.
You send a postal order and
they send you the dress!
I know what a catalogue is, thank you.
I'm too old to think a new
dress will solve anything much.
Well, you're not wasting
money, that's for sure.
Mama! What are you doing here?
I wasn't expecting you.
I want to be quite certain you're thinking sensibly
about the possible changes at the hospital.
By thinking sensibly, you
mean thinking like you.
Of course.
Cora believes you're wrong.
Cora is confused.
And when she sees sense,
she'll agree with you?
You have been talking to Isobel.
Since they made her the almoner,
she's never been the same.
- I have been talking to Cora.
- That is a mistake.
You can't expect me to avoid
talking to my own wife!
Why not? I know several couples who are
perfectly happy, haven't spoken in years.
Hello, Granny! They
didn't say you were here.
I'm here to make sure of your
father in the coming fight.
I'm off to London to calm my editor.
Say goodbye to Mama.
Will you stay with Rosamund?
I don't know how long I'll be
there. So I'll stay at the flat.
Is it proper for a young
woman to be alone in a flat?
Granny, Adrienne Bolland flew alone
over the Andes mountains four years ago.
Anyway, I'm not a young woman.
I'm staring middle age in the face.
- Granny!
- Have you seen your mama?
She's just finishing off
the menus with Mrs Patmore.
Then I will be off.
Why not stay and say hello?
Oh... I have a feeling Cora and I will be
saying hello rather less than... en garde!
.. in the next few weeks.
Right.
What if we keep the Dover sole
and change the cod to a crown roast?
- I'll do peaches in brandy.
- That sounds more like it.
Thank you, Mrs Patmore.
- Is everything else all right?
- Yes, Your Ladyship.
That is... I'm a bit
concerned about the wedding.
Why is that? Don't hesitate to
charge it all to the house account.
Oh, very kind, I'm sure.
But it's not that.
- Mrs Hughes isn't happy.
- I'm sorry to hear it.
- Is she regretting her decision?
- It's not her decision she regrets
so much as his decision.
What is that?
A stamp to mark the
British Empire exhibition.
Just been released. First
commemorative stamp ever.
What's that great lion doing?
It's the lion of Britain
with the head of the king.
Hm! I think it's silly.
Because you understand nothing.
I'll go.
- Ahem.
- Who was that?
- Who was... what?
- Whoever was outside.
- Was nobody.
- Very talkative for a nobody.
I meant... He'd come to the wrong house.
Haven't we all?
- Did Lady Edith get off OK?
- As far as I know.
I can't think why she doesn't sack the
wretched man and find someone else.
Unless she enjoys racing up to London
in a swirling cloud of crisis and drama.
I've had rather a sad
letter from Mr Branson.
Listen.
I dreamt last night I was
in the park at Downton,
walking with Sybbie under the great trees,
listening to the pigeons
cooing in their branches.
And when I woke, my eyes
were filled with tears.
- That's very moving.
- I agree.
I owe him a letter.
I'll write after Carson's wedding.
Talking of which, I feel
sorry for Mrs Hughes.
I said I'd brighten up her frock for her.
When she gave it me, it was an old day
dress. There wasn't much I could do.
Can't I lend her a brooch or something?
I told Mrs Patmore and she said not
to worry. Maybe she's got a plan.
Let's hope so.
Have you given any more
thought to Mr Ryder's advice?
I have.
You're not...
- Too early to tell.
- Lord knows the problem isn't Bates!
Honestly, My Lady! If I repeated some
of the things you say downstairs...
Should you be working? I can
manage. And there's always Baxter.
No, Mr Bates would smell a rat.
I don't want him to know anything until
it's worked and I'm almost showing.
He'd put so much on to it.
At the end of the third month, I'll invent
an appointment and we'll whizz up to London!
- How exciting!
- I don't want to be excited.
Not until I know it's going to happen.
Looking for a place, Mr Barrow?
I might be. Would you be sorry?
They've not said anything though.
Mr Carson is hoping I'll resign.
To avoid any possible
unpleasantness, that's all.
What do you think of this?
Experienced manservant required
for a position of trust
in a prominent household.
Sounds interesting. Where is it?
I'm only looking in the Yorkshire
papers. I want to stay up here.
Careful, Mr Barrow. Someone might accuse
you of having feelings for the area.
Would that be so hard to believe?
Harder for you to accept
than for us to believe.
Am I here tonight without cousin Violet
to cement my alliance with Cora?
No, not at all!
Carson, could you ask Mrs Hughes
to join us in the drawing room?
Mrs Hughes, My Lady?
I want to ask her something and
I'd like Lady Mary to be there.
- What are you getting at?
- Carson?
Of course, Your Ladyship.
Shall we go through? Are
you staying tonight, Robert?
No, I don't want to miss anything.
Does cousin Violet know
I'm here this evening?
Not unless you've told her.
I don't want her to think
I'm plotting against her.
- Aren't you?
- Yes.
But I don't want her to know.
Her Ladyship is going to help Mr Mason.
When I was in the drawing room,
she almost said it out loud!
Let's hope so.
Now, will you let me take
you through the exam papers?
- Are you losing confidence in me?
- No, it's not that.
I'm sure you know the answers.
But sometimes it can be hard
to make out the question.
Mr Molesley, shall we ask them
to come down and help themselves?
- Sorry, Mr Carson.
- Is Mrs Hughes in her room?
As far as I know.
- How may I help, My Lady?
- I'm sorry to put you on the spot.
But I believe you've been rather
railroaded over your reception.
I understand you don't want
to be married from this house.
- What?
- Why ever not?
My Lady, we're both honoured
to be allowed the privilege --
No. I want to hear from Mrs Hughes.
Your Ladyship, I have no
wish to sound ungrateful.
This is a fine house.
And Mr Carson's right.
It would be an honour
to hold our party here.
But it's not what you want.
Well, to start with, I'd like a kind of reception
that's different from the ones you're used to.
With a solid meal served at proper tables.
Does anyone have a sit-down
wedding breakfast any more?
A great many people, My Lady.
And then I'd like to feel
we could ask all sorts.
Everyone who's been
part of our lives here.
And I'd planned for music later on.
And maybe a bit of a hoolie.
None of which would be
suitable in the Great Hall.
- It would not.
- There you are, we're agreeing.
Mrs Hughes, doesn't Carson
deserve a wedding in this house?
Where he has served this family
for so long and with such loyalty.
And will continue to do so while
there is breath in his body.
Well, then.
But this is our day, My Lady.
It's about Charles
Carson and Elsie Hughes.
And not about this glorious house or the
glorious people who have lived in it.
Just us, and that's the way
I'd like to celebrate it.
I couldn't understand more, Mrs Hughes.
I hope we'll be invited.
Of course you will all be invited.
We'd be honoured if you come.
But it would be our day,
celebrated in our way.
Do you know where you
will stage this festivity?
I had thought about the
schoolhouse, My Lord.
But Mr Carson doesn't care for it.
I don't mind the schoolhouse.
Right, then it would seem to be settled.
Thank you, Mrs Hughes.
Thank you, My Lady.
- Why did we have to listen to that?!
- I want you to stop bullying them.
- And let them do it their way.
- You think I'm a bully?
- I think you're a snob.
- How do you make that out?
She didn't want the bother of a
servants' wedding in the hall.
That's not fair. We...
Ahem.
Going out, Mr Spratt?
Do I have your permission?
You can go round the world
as far as I'm concerned.
That's very considerate of you.
But a breath of air is all I need.
Denker, I wonder if I might have
something warm to drink before I go up.
Yes, certainly, My Lady.
How about a nice cup of hot chocolate?
Oh, just the thing. Thank you.
- Um...
- Yes?
My Lady, Mr Spratt seems very
preoccupied at the moment.
I wondered if you knew what it was about.
Does this spring from a
concern for his welfare?
We all have to rub along
together, don't we?
Well, it would be nice if we could.
I worry. Perhaps one of
his friends is in trouble.
I know nothing of Spratt's friends.
I know he has a great many relations
who seem to get married and
buried with numbing regularity.
Usually on very inconvenient days.
Perhaps it's one of them?
Why don't you ask him?
While you're making my chocolate.
Yes, My Lady. Of course.
Oh, My Lord. A quick word.
It may be that we have a painless
solution to the problem of Barrow.
Oh, yes?
He's applying for a job in the vicinity.
Do you know of a house
called Dryden Park, near York?
The name rings a bell. I think
my parents used to go there.
But I haven't heard anything about it
for years. Is that where he's off to?
- Hopefully. We shall see.
- Ahem.
- Are you quite well?
- Oh, yes.
Just a bit of indigestion.
Carson.
I hope you weren't upset by that
business in the drawing room.
Not at all, My Lady. As a matter
of fact, I don't believe Her Ladyship
was acting for snobbish reasons.
Perhaps not. But it annoys me to see
you cheated of your just desserts.
- I wanted the best for you.
- And I shall have it, My Lady.
If you attend the wedding,
that's enough for me.
Good night.
- Yes?
- Hello.
I telephoned earlier in
response to the advertisement.
- Name's Barrow.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
Lady Edith Crawley?
- It is you, isn't it?
- Hello...
Bertie Pelham. We met at Brancaster
when it was let to Lord Sinderby.
Of course! I'm sorry to be so
dense. I remember you very well.
You're the agent. Or you were then.
I am now. Business has brought
me to London for a few days.
Me too.
In fact, it's the longest time I've
spent in London since my cousin came out.
She was with us at
Brancaster. Rose Aldridge.
I remember. I thought you
were a very jolly party.
I told Lord Hexham he should try and
let to the Sinderbys again this year!
Are you having a good time in London?
Well, I've been working since I arrived.
- And missing Marigold, of course.
- Marigold?
My... That is, my ward.
- Our ward.
- Of course.
You told me about her.
- I'd better get on.
- I expect you're busy.
I'm not usually, but I've got rather
a drama on my hands with my magazine.
You've probably forgotten,
but I own a magazine.
Indeed I have not. I thought
it was incredibly modern.
It's incredibly complicated at the moment.
Which is why I have to
get back to the office.
I don't suppose you'd like
a drink with me later on.
- Well...
- Only I'm going home tomorrow.
And I'm not sure when I'll be back.
All right. Why not?
But it will have to be near the office.
We're in Covent Garden.
What about Rules? Will they
let us have a drink there?
I should think so. Shall we say seven?
I'm going to hurry away
before you change your mind!
Perhaps you could tell me a
little more about the job, Mr...
Reresby. Sir Michael Reresby.
Oh.
As you can see, we've
rather let things slide.
It's been very difficult
since my wife died.
I can imagine, Sir Michael.
She was a lady in waiting, do you know?
- To the old Duchess of Connaught. - Ah.
Do you have any other family?
Two sons.
But they... They never
came back from the war.
Very sorry to hear that.
- Did you serve?
- I was in Flanders, yes.
I served. I got this there.
That's what I need. Someone who knows about
fighting for his king and his country.
I expect this was a wonderful
house for entertaining.
Oh, you should have seen it!
We had such fun in those days.
Do you know what I shall always remember?
The women going up to bed
at the end of the evening.
Their faces lit by the
flame from the candle.
Yes, diamonds twinkling
as they climbed up into the darkness.
Shall we go through here?
As you can see, it's all rather silted up.
- Can you clear a space?
- Of course.
So can you let me know more about the job?
How many staff do you have?
Well, there's Mrs Tonkins. She
comes in three days a week.
And she has to manage everything?
We do have a man outside
every now and then.
But that's why we need you.
In your advertisement, you spoke of a position
of trust, Sir Michael, in a prominent household.
This is a very prominent household.
Can you doubt it?
We have entertained not
just the Connaughts,
but the Fife princesses!
Both of them. The Duke of
Argyll. The Queen of Spain.
Yes... But that was some time ago.
Are you a republican?
No. I don't believe so, but then I've
never really thought about it much.
Well, think about it now!
I can't risk a republican in this
household when anyone might call!
Maybe you're right. Maybe
I'm not quite up to it.
Philosophically.
Thank heavens we picked that
up before he caused any trouble!
I should be going.
I hope you find the man
you're looking for.
We can't let them down, do you see?
When the good times return,
they will all come back.
We must be ready.
Can't let our standards slip.
No.
And good luck with those standards.
This is what you had
in mind for the cover?
No, don't touch that!
It does seem similar to
last month's, Mr Skinner.
Don't be so absurd. Please!
Where is the copy for this?
Mr Skinner, this really isn't finished.
I have dealt with amateurism.
I've even dealt with incompetence.
But this ridiculous, muddle-headed
meddling just about --
Mr Skinner! That's quite enough.
If that's how you feel, I suggest
we part company once and for all.
I've done it. He's gone.
Good riddance.
And well done.
But what happens now?
We have to get it out by tomorrow.
We have to get the proofs
to the printers by 4am.
- You can't mean to do it yourself.
- Why not?
I refuse to be defeated by a
petulant and overweight tyrant.
I'll lay out the articles as usual.
It's seven o'clock.
Which means we have nine hours.
We'd better get some coffee on and...
Oh, crikey!
I won't be long.
Keep getting the copy together.
- May I help you, madam?
- I won't be long.
I'm so, so sorry. Believe me, if you knew
what I'm living through, you'd forgive me.
- I forgive you anyway.
- I can't have a drink.
I'd love to, but I can't.
My editor has walked out.
I have to get the magazine to the
printers by four in the morning.
So it's sandwiches and
coffee and work until dawn.
- All right.
- You're a darling. Thank you.
Do telephone me if and when
you're up in London again.
No, I meant all right, I'll come with you.
- Come with me where?
- Back to the office.
I can make coffee. I can fetch sandwiches.
I can... carry bits of paper around.
- Shouldn't we get going?
- Aren't you having dinner somewhere?
I thought that's why
you hadn't suggested it.
No, I didn't think you'd accept dinner. I
planned to ask you halfway through the drink.
Right, well, we should get back.
So it's just the causes of the war.
Both wars.
The Spanish succession and the Austrian
succession. You're comparing them.
Don't forget. Keep it
simple and straightforward.
What is it?
Oh...
I don't know if I should tell you.
Tell me if it's important.
Don't if it's not.
It might be.
When I was serving tea in the library,
I heard them say that the Drewes
are giving up Yew Tree Farm.
That's what she was thinking!
Her Ladyship knew they were
going to hand in the lease.
She couldn't decide
whether to say anything!
- Don't jump the gun.
- I knew she'd had an idea. I said it!
You've made me so happy! This is
just the tonic Mr Mason needs.
- But it's not definite yet.
- I'll say that. I'll tell him that.
But he'll be made up.
Who's that?
Somebody at the back door.
Never mind. Mrs Porter can answer
it. It's probably a delivery.
At this time?
Mr Willis, what brings you here?
I'm sorry to call so late.
But I've had an enquiry
which concerns you.
Mm, I'm all ears!
Mr Spratt, do you know a Mr Wally Stern?
Yes, he's my sister's son.
He's been serving time in York prison.
Oh.
Is it absolutely necessary
for Miss Denker to be present?
- Killjoy.
- She'll be questioned next.
So what's the point in
asking her to leave?
Thank you, Sergeant.
I'm aware of the present situation
of my unfortunate nephew.
Not the present situation, I'm afraid.
Mr Stern recently absconded from prison.
He's currently on the run.
Someone answering his description
has been seen in this neighbourhood.
Naturally, we wondered if
he'd tried to make contact.
Not with me, Sergeant, no.
Miss Denker, can you add anything?
No.
Nothing that leads you to suppose
a man was hanging around the house?
I'm afraid not, Sergeant.
Perhaps the identification was a mistake.
Is he very distinctive to look at?
Um... Not very. Quite ordinary, in fact.
All right.
Well, that would seem to be that.
I'll say goodbye.
Of course, if he tries to get in touch...
We'll be on to you in a moment.
I'm sorry. I don't know why
he wanted to drag you into it.
What an interesting family
you have, Mr Spratt.
Mine are quite dull by comparison.
I haven't seen him for years.
It's your sister I feel sorry for.
- She has done nothing to deserve it.
- Of course not.
I do have one question though.
What's that?
After you put him up in the potting shed,
did he get away safely?
- What's the idea?
- Lady Eltham's costume ball.
I can't decide which guests
are the most important.
Never mind that. Best
clothes and prettiest faces.
Nobody cares about anything else.
You have the address.
They're waiting for you.
He's got everything he needs.
- Put it into Mr Brent's hands.
- Yes, ma'am.
- I'll get you some more coffee.
- Would you?
- Well, you did it.
- We did it.
I really am so grateful.
Are you an editor now?
Does this count in your profession
as a sort of baptism of blood?
I don't know what will happen next.
But it's nice to know I
can do it if I have to.
You certainly can.
I won't though. Not yet.
I'll put someone in charge as a caretaker.
Then I'll think.
In the end, the question must be
are you a country woman or a townie?
It's more than that.
I know now I need a purpose.
That's what I've learned.
I can't just lead one of
those purposeless lives.
You inspire me.
Not many people would say that.
They would if they knew you.
Thank you, Audrey.
So you go home today.
Yes. I'll catch the twelve o'clock
and try and sleep on the train!
What about you?
I'll settle in the new
editor and go back after that.
Our butler is getting married on Saturday.
- Which is quite a big thing.
- Has he been with you a long time?
Forever. He joined us as a junior
footman in my grandfather's day.
I love those stories.
I wonder how much longer
people will tell them.
I know.
Let's not be sad, not today.
After all, we've just edited a magazine.
This just came for you.
- Oh, thank you very much.
- What is it?
Never you mind.
Oh, what a relief! I thought
it wasn't going to get here.
May we know what it is?
It's a frock I ordered as
a surprise for Mrs Hughes.
But with the wedding tomorrow,
I thought we'd missed it.
- Can we have a look?
- Don't see why not.
- Just check Mr Carson's gone.
- It's a relief to me as well.
The one she wanted to wear was awful.
Oh.
Well, it's very...
It's an improvement, we can say that.
Is it? What was the last one like?!
I don't understand. It was
so nice in the picture.
It wasn't dear but... It
seemed like a bargain.
It's the thought that counts.
Not with a frock, it's not!
Lady Mary says she'll lend
her a brooch or something.
A brooch? She'll need a diamond
parure to make this look any good.
She's coming!
Daisy, I'm afraid Gertie's ill,
so can I ask you to do the fires?
I'm sorry to get you up so early.
That's all right, My Lady.
Are you sure you don't want any breakfast?
No. I've had a cup of tea. That's enough.
I'm having luncheon in York
after I see the hospital.
Daisy, you don't do the bedroom
fires these days, do you?
Not as a rule, My Lady, no.
But Gertie's unwell. And we don't
have a proper scullery maid any more.
I'm afraid I'm not usually
up early enough to know that.
I just wanted to say how
very grateful I am, My Lady.
- Grateful? For what?
- When you said you had a plan.
It was because the Drewes might be
leaving Yew Tree Farm, wasn't it?
- Well...
- I know you can't say anything.
But I'm so thankful to you for trying.
Is something the matter, My Lady?
- I hope she wasn't bothering you.
- No, but...
Never mind.
We'll see what happens.
Do you remember I thought Mrs Patmore might
have an idea about Mrs Hughes's dress?
She did, and it arrived this morning.
- No good?
- No good at all.
Horrible, in fact. And it's too
late now to order anything else.
Can't we lend her a dress?
She wouldn't fit into a dress of yours.
- And Her Ladyship is too tall.
- An embroidered evening coat?
The length wouldn't matter so much.
I'll ask Mama when I get up.
Miss Baxter said she was
leaving early to go into York.
That's right. She's out all day.
She goes straight from York
to a meeting with Dr Clarkson.
We'll have to manage without her.
She won't mind. She'll be pleased.
I um...
.. just want to make sure
everything is under control.
I think so. Mr Brock is bringing the
flowers and foliage in the morning.
And Mrs Patmore is on top of things.
Are you nervous?
A little. And I'm sad about my dress.
I wish I'd made more of an effort.
But it's too late now.
I'm sure you'll look wonderful.
- Well, I'll look tidy.
- What about tonight?
We mustn't see each other tonight.
I'm having dinner in here.
And they'll warn you when I'm going
up so we don't meet on the stairs!
Am I hearing right?
You went behind our backs and
betrayed us to the enemy?
Whose enemy? They're not my enemy.
I asked to see the Royal Yorkshire.
And to meet with the doctors in charge
so I could learn the benefits of a merger.
Today, they were good enough to
give me a tour and a luncheon.
- Am I to think ill of them for that?
- And you don't call that betrayal?
It's called being in
possession of the facts.
I wondered when we'd hear from you.
It's unfortunate if you've given them the
impression that we approve of the plan.
But I do approve of it.
And you're the fount
of wisdom on this topic!
I don't claim to know
more than any of you.
I'm glad you don't claim to know
more than I do, Lady Grantham.
- But I am disappointed.
- And we know why.
If we don't, I gather we will soon.
I'm afraid you see the new arrangement
as diminishing your own importance.
- What?
- You're the king of this place.
But once it's a wing of the Royal
Yorkshire, you'll be one more local doctor.
With some authority, yes.
But it will not be the same.
- Mrs Crawley doesn't mean that.
- I'd like to think that.
But it sounds very much as if she does.
Did you drink at luncheon?
No, I did not. Which you know
very well since we were together.
Not all the time.
Shall we call a halt to this
before we say things we will regret?
I rather hope Mrs Crawley
regrets what she's said already.
I'm going home.
In future, let's try to manage
things in a more civilised manner.
Goodbye, Dr Clarkson.
Goodbye, Lady Grantham.
Has tea gone up?
Not yet, oh great one.
How did you get on at Dryden Park?
It wasn't right for me, Mr Carson.
Pity. Mr Molesley, Andrew, tea.
- Won't be long now.
- Something will turn up.
I expect you will be glad
to see the back of me.
If it's what you want.
- He means it too.
- Don't fish.
Especially where they're
never going to bite.
- You've got me wrong.
You all have. - How?
I don't want anything
from Andy but friendship.
We were friends when he first came. I
helped to get him the job, for God's sake!
But now you've all poisoned
his mind against me.
- Then tell him.
- It's too late.
The damage has been done.
You don't believe me anyway.
Mrs Hughes.
Can you pop up to Her
Ladyship's room for a moment?
- Whatever for?
- Lady Mary has a surprise for you.
A surprise? For me?
Why?
You're getting married tomorrow. That
might have something to do with it.
Can we meet there at five?
Here she is, the famous editor!
Trailing streamers of success.
This is the mock-up.
It does seem weird that
we managed it in time.
We managed it?
The office. We all pulled together.
I think it's perfectly
brilliant, darling. Don't you?
I'm back, but I'm going
upstairs to get straight.
- And to calm down.
- Why? How was your day?
The morning was interesting.
The afternoon was ghastly.
Oh, Mama, you'll find...
See? That dress doesn't look bad now
as a foil to set off the
colours of the embroidery.
I agree. It's plainness is a virtue.
And I'm sure we can do
something about the length.
Excuse me? Will someone
explain to me what's going on?
- Didn't Lady Mary tell you, My Lady?
- Tell me what?
That Mrs Hughes is going to borrow
one of your coats to be married in.
Was I to have any say in this as
you rifle through my cupboards?
Your Ladyship, there's obviously
been a misunderstanding.
I'm surprised at you, Mrs Hughes.
This is not the kind of behaviour
I would look for from you.
We'll hang them up at once
and leave you in peace.
Lady Mary said --
Lady Mary may dispose of her
own clothes as she sees fit.
But I do not know what gives her
the right to dispose of mine.
Now please leave me. I have a
headache and I need to lie down.
- You're very prompt.
- Oh, My Lady.
We've had an awful business.
Her Ladyship walked in when Mrs
Hughes was trying on the coats.
I don't know. She seemed to
think we were stealing them.
- Don't be silly.
- I'm not.
I've never seen her so angry.
Poor Mrs Hughes. She feels awful.
We can't have that on the day
before her wedding. Leave it to me.
Yes?
I hope Anna's wrong, but she seems to
think you wouldn't lend Mrs Hughes a coat.
I just walked in and they
were putting on my clothes.
Please tell me you weren't rude.
Your mother has had a horrible afternoon with
Granny. They were at each other's throats.
Does that excuse insulting a woman who
has served us faithfully for many years,
who simply wanted something
nice to be married in?
- Why didn't you tell me?
- I tried to but you stormed off.
What was Mrs Hughes doing in there?
Typical though, isn't it?
30 years of service, one wrong move,
and... snap, you're out on your ear.
They're very appreciative of our service.
It was not a wrong move and
she is not out on her ear.
I won't speak ill of Her Ladyship.
Not when she's doing what
she's doing for Mr Mason.
- What's this?
- Daisy.
- You must talk when it isn't settled.
- I want to get things settled.
Don't we all?
You seem unusually disenchanted
with life these days, Mr Barrow.
I can't see the future, Mr Carson.
But then, I suppose, none of us can.
Don't let it upset you.
It does upset me.
I felt like a naughty
child in need of a smack.
Anyway, I'm going up now. It's past ten.
Yes?
- May I come in?
- Please.
Mrs Hughes, I won't beat about the bush.
I behaved badly earlier.
I hope you'll accept my apology.
It must have been strange to
find us all there, My Lady.
Nevertheless, I have no
excuse to behave as I did.
Not to someone who deserves
our loyalty as you do.
- Please forgive me.
- Of course.
I can only say I was angry about
something quite different.
I allowed it to cloud my judgement.
We've all done that, My Lady.
Finally, I'd like you to have this coat.
I... I'm not sure it was a good idea.
Please. Or I'll feel I've spoiled the day,
which is the very last thing I'd want to do.
Furthermore, I want you to keep it.
Well, I...
I've asked Baxter to fit it for you
tonight. She's happy to do that.
Very well, My Lady. I'm very grateful.
I'm not sure when I'll wear it again.
- But you never know.
- You never do.
- I'll say good night.
- Good night, Your Ladyship.
- For Mr Carson.
- Thank you.
Come in.
Thank you, Mrs Patmore.
That's lovely.
- What's happened? What's the matter?
- Nothing's the matter.
We've come to dress the bride.
There's a sentence I
never thought I'd hear.
Ring and...
Ring.
Ohh...
- Mr Brock brought these for you.
- What are they?
They're roses with
heather for buttonholes.
He's done that to one of Mrs Hughes'.
- Very nice, but whom are they for?
- For you and your ushers.
My ushers? I've not got any ushers.
- Perhaps you should
have, Mr Carson. - Oh...
Take one for yourself. Give one to Andrew.
- Remove the fern.
- What about me, Mr Carson?
Take one. I might as well be
hanged for a sheep as a lamb.
For better, for worse,
for richer, for poorer,
in sickness and in health,
to love, cherish, and to obey,
till death us do part.
According to God's holy ordinance...
With this ring, I thee wed.
With my body, I thee worship.
All my worldly goods, I thee endow.
In the name of the Father and of the
Son, and of the Holy Ghost, Amen.
Ohh...
I now pronounce you man and wife together.
Oh, thank you.
- I'm so glad to see you here.
- Couldn't miss Carson's wedding.
I felt uncomfortable about the
way I spoke to you the other day.
- You said what you thought.
- I don't think I did. Not truly.
I was exasperated by Lady Grantham.
And you got in the way.
Don't be too quick to condemn
yourself. I'm not sure you were wrong.
Maybe I haven't focused on
what's best for the village.
What is this?
Dr Clarkson is reviewing his position.
I hope this is wishful
thinking on Mrs Crawley's part.
To be honest, I don't know.
But if something is that important,
it's worth considering more than once.
Really? In my experience, second
thoughts are vastly overrated.
But we mustn't be too blinkered, surely?
It's not just Mrs Crawley
and Lady Grantham.
Your old friend Lord Merton
is in favour of reform.
A peer in favour of reform. It's
like a turkey in favour of Christmas.
Nice to see you here.
- A wonderful service.
- Thank you, My Lord.
Please understand that
nothing is going to change.
I doubt you'd agree, Mrs... Carson.
We'll try to keep the
changes manageable, My Lady.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
I'm so happy for you. I'm sorry if I
made things awkward about the reception.
Please forgive me.
My Lady, Mr Carson would forgive you
if you attacked him with a brick!
You don't have to worry,
you know, Mr Spratt.
No?
I can keep secrets when I want to.
Maybe. But the question
remains, will you want to?
Ah, mm.
You're very sunny again.
- I love weddings, don't you?
- I liked mine.
You would tell me if you'd
fallen in love with someone else?
I shouldn't think so. Not for a moment.
Because there's something
about you just now.
And there's something about you, Mr Bates.
There's definitely something about you.
There she is now.
You won't regret it. She's
more than equal to the task.
In fact, I think she'll do you credit.
I think she'll do you credit, Mr Molesley.
You seem to have been an
excellent influence in all this.
Well, I believe that education is the
gate that leads to any future worth having.
Have you missed your vocation?
I've missed everything, Mr Dawes.
But Daisy doesn't have to.
Mr Mason is so full of
gratitude, Your Ladyship.
It's like a dream after
a nightmare, My Lady.
But please, you mustn't think...
May I have silence?
Thank you.
Mr Barrow.
Before we take our seats,
I believe, as the groom,
that I have the right to a few words.
I will not be prolix,
but it must be right that I mark that
I am the happiest and luckiest of men.
That a woman of such grace and charm
should entrust her life's
happiness to my unworthy charge...
.. passeth all understanding.
To my wonderful bride.
The bride and groom!
To the bride and groom.
Ohh!
Tom!
And Sybbie, darling!
What are you doing here?
And how did you know where to find us?
The hall boy on duty
told me where you were.
It means that I can
congratulate you in person.
Mr and Mrs Carson.
- Oh, are you back for a holiday?
- Say you'll stay!
That's just the point.
I can stay as long as you want me.
I don't understand. What are you saying?
Just this. That I've come back
and I'd like to stay for good.
- If Lord Grantham will have me.
- Of course we'll have you!
- We'll be delighted!
- I echo every syllable.
Hello, darling Sybbie!
Give old Donk a kiss!
Tom, this is such wonderful
news. Are you sure?
I'm really, really sure.
So what happened?
It's quite simple.
I had to go all the way to
Boston to figure something out.
- But that's what I did.
- What was it?
I learned that Downton is my home.
And that you are my family.
If I didn't quite know that
before I left, I know it now.
- Sybbie!
- Marigold!
Hello.
If I am to live out my life here, I need
something to do that isn't just the estate.
- How enterprising.
- We talk about making a difference.
But this could actually change lives.
Hasn't got time to greet her old friends.
When were you a friend of Gwen's?
No-one has sharper eyes than a loving son.
You read that somewhere.
You're not hiding anything?
- Don't give me not possible!
- All right, madam! Finish that mash!
Cousin Isobel is entitled
to put up an argument.
Of course. She's just
not entitled to win it!